A Finding Aid to the Peter Howard Selz papers, 1929-2014, bulk 1950-2005, in the Archives of American Art AAA.selzpete
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1942-2011; Series 2; 7.8 Linear feet Box 3-10, OV 32
  - Books, 1942-2007; 2.1
    - Beyond the Mainstream (Box 6)
      - Notes, circa 1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - "Discards", circa 1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Royalty Statements, 1995-2012 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Permissions for Image Rights and Reproductions, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
      - Photographs of Artwork, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
      - Photocopies of Illustrations, circa 1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Illustrations and Introduction Draft, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Outline, circa 1995 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - "Own Copies" of Essays for Book, circa 1995 (Box 6, Folder 20-23)
    - Beyond the Mainstream Galleys, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Chillida (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, 1984-1997 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
      - Harry Abrams Book Contract, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - "Chillida: Two Public Spaces in the Basque Country" Essay Draft, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Notes and Printed Material for "Public Spaces" Essay, circa 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Art Inventories and Bibliographies, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Photocopies of Eduardo Chillida Photographs, 1958-1984 (Box 7, Folder 11)
        Photocopies of Eduardo Chillida and other people at various events.
      - Notes, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Printed Material, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Chillida Typescript Draft, circa 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Photocopy of Finalized Chillida Manuscript, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
        Oversized material house in OV 32.
      - Miscellaneous Material, circa 1984 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - German Expressionist Painting Bound Typescript Draft, circa 1957 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Sam Francis (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 7, Folder 18-20)
      - Undated Correspondence, circa 1970-1976 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Index Cards with Notes, circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Notes, circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
      - Exhibition Announcements, 1961-1978 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Printed Material, 1952-1973 (Box 7, Folder 26-28)
      - Photographs of Sam Francis and Others, 1959-1972 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Early Manuscript Draft, circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 30-31)
      - Later Manuscript Draft, circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 32-33)
      - Final Manuscript Draft, circa 1975 (Box 7, Folder 34-35)
    - Sam Francis Material for Revised Edition, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Theories and Documents of Contemporary Art (Box 8)
      - John Hallmark Neff Correspondence, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Richard Hertz Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Scott Norton Correspondence, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - University of California Press Correspondence, 1982-1995 (Box 8, Folder 5-8)
      - Publisher and Artist Permissions, circa 1994 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Chapter 1 Illustrations, circa 1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Chapter 3 Illustrations, circa 1995 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Chapter 6 Illustrations, circa 1995 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Reader Feedback Reports, 1984-1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Royalties and Reader Feedback, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1995 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Preface and Introduction Drafts, 1991-1994 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Table of Contents, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Chapter 1 Drafts, circa 1995 (Box 8, Folder 18-22)
      - Chapter 2 Drafts, circa 1995 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
    - Theories and Documents of Contemporary Art (Box 9)
      - Chapter 3 Drafts, circa 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1-6)
      - Chapter 4 "Pop Selections" Drafts, circa 1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Chapter 4 "Pop Discards" Printed Material, circa 1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Chapter 6 Drafts, circa 1995 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
      - Chapter 6 "Discards" Printed Material, circa 1995 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Chapter 10 Drafts, circa 1995 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Theories of Modern Art (Box 9)
      - Herschel Chipp and Joshua Taylor Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - University of California Press Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - General Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Royalties and Reader Feedback, 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Research Material on Artists, circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Typescript Drafts of Essays, circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Book Outline and Essay Draft, circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Notes and Printed Material, circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Bibliographic Notes, circa 1968 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - William Congdon (Box 9)
      - Foundation for Improving Understanding of the Arts Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - William Congdon Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 23)
        Includes a mixture of photocopies and originals of correspondence.
      - General Correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Foundation for Improving Understanding of the Arts Essay Proposal, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Biographical Material, circa 1981-1988 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - William Congdon (Box 10)
      - Notes, circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "William Congdon, American Painter" Early Typescript Draft, circa 1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - "William Congdon" Final Typescript Draft, circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - "The Workshop of the Artist" by Rodolfo Balzarotti, circa 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - "The Art of William Congdon" by Fred Licht, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Photocopy of In the Death of One, 1942-1945, circa 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Photocopies of "Letters to Jim", 1950-1959 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Transcripts of Letters to Belle Gardner, 1948-1958 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Transcripts from Artist Notebooks, 1948-1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Transcript of Conversation between Rodolfo Balzarotti, Cacciari, and Peter Selz, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Photographs of Artist, circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Black and White Photographs of Art, 1950-1977 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Color Photographs of Art, 1942-1989 (Box 10, Folder 13-15)
      - Printed Material, 1975-1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Oversized Chillida Manuscript Photocopy from Box 7, Folder 15, 1986 (Box OV 32)
  - Other Writings, 1963-2011; 2.2
    The bulk of this subseries consists of drafts of articles, essays, and lectures by Peter Selz. A few writings by others are grouped together at the end of the subseries.
    This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Assorted Lectures, circa 1963-circa 1967 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      Includes typescript drafts from a folder titled "Lectures - Various."
    - Assorted Articles and Book Reviews, 1963-1977 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - University of California, Berkeley, Commencement Address, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "A Modern Looks at Itself", circa 1985 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Book Review of Art in the San Francisco Bay Area, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Impact from Abroad" Galleys and Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "The Impact of Artists from Abroad" Early Essay Drafts, circa 1992; Includes 1 floppy disk. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "The Impact from Abroad" Later Drafts, circa 1992 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Americans Abroad", circa 1993 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Abstract Classicism Reexamined", circa 1996 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1970-circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "Chicago: The City of Surrealism" by Mary Jacob, circa 1985 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - The Religious Art of Pablo Picasso by Jane Dillenberger and John Handley, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Professional Files, 1949-2012; Series 3; 1 Linear feet Box 11
  Found here are files relating to Peter Selz’s professional appointments at various universities and museums. Included within are materials related to his faculty and curatorial appointments at the Institute of Design at the Illinois Institute of Technology, the Museum of Modern Art, Pomona College, and the University of California, Berkeley. Files consist of teaching contracts, recommendations for students and colleagues, course syllabuses, and correspondence negotiating salary and promotions.
  - Banff Centre Guest Lecturer Appointment, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Center for Art, Religion, and Education (CARE), 2007-2008 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Includes syllabus and student papers on a course about
  - City University of New York Faculty Appointment, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem Visiting Professorship, 1975-1977 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Design at the Illinois Institute of Technology (Box 11)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1955 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Research for Essay, circa 1950 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material, circa 1955-circa 1990 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
    - "Modernism Comes to Chicago" Drafts, circa 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 9-11)
  - Museum of Modern Art Curatorship, 1958-1967 (Box 11, Folder 12-15)
  - Museum of Modern Art Printed Material, 1958-1967 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Museum of Modern Art Miscellaneous Material, 1958-1967 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Pomona College Professorship, 1955-1964 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - University of California, Berkeley (Box 11)
    - "Art in the Weimar Republic" Seminar, 1967-1988 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Promotion, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Retirement Party, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Recommendation for Celeste Connor, 2002-2005 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Recommendation for Terrence E. Dempsey, 1997-2003 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Recommendation for John Handley, 2012 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Recommendation for Lissa Tyler Renaud, 2003-2005 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Assorted Recommendations, 2002-2008 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Grant Applications, 1973-2001 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Project Files, 1962-2008; Series 4; 2.6 Linear feet Box 12-14, OV 33
  Found here are files for various art projects, panels, symposiums, and conservation plans that were organized by Selz or in which he participated. There are extensive files for the Berkeley Art Project which involved a competition for a sculpture to memorialize the Free Speech Movement, Christo’s Running Fence for which Selz acted as a project director, the Disney Art Project, and the “Funk Art” and “Art and Politics in the 20th Century” symposiums. Files vary but usually contain correspondence, printed material, maps, financial records, reports, grant applications, and other related material. There are 2 tape reels, 1 VHS, and 1 sound cassette.
  This series is organized in rough alphabetical order by project title, and further arranged by document type within each project file.
  - 9th and 10th Annual Congress of the American-Romanian Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1984-1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Art and Politics in the 20th Century Symposium and Anthology, 1968-1981 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Art for Democracy Project, 1982-1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Artists Call (Box 12)
    - Exhibition and Events Planning Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Writing and Notes, circa 1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material, circa 1984 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies Program Residency, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley Art Project (Box 12)
    - Berkeley Administration Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - General Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Free Speech Movement History, circa 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Art Competition Planning and Announcements, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Free Speech Movement 25th Anniversary Publicity, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Free Speech Memorial Competition Poster, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Benefit Art Auction, circa 1989 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - National Endowment for the Arts Application, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Fund Raising Material, 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Financial Records, 1990-1994 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Competition Jury, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Final Selection Committee, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Design Competition Finalists, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Public Exhibition and Finalists Exhibition, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Mark A. Brest van Kempen, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Deed of Gift for Mark A. Brest van Kempen Artwork, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Dedication Ceremony, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - News Clippings on Monument Controversy, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Printed Material, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - "Other Competitions" Applications, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Center for the Study of Political Graphics Murals, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Christo's Running Fence (Box 12)
    - Christo and Jeanne-Claude Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - General Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Christo's Running Fence (Box 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1975-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    - Undated Correspondence, 1973-1980 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Notes, circa 1973-circa 1980 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Project Proposal Outline and Drafts, circa 1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Photographs of Running Fence, circa 1972-1976 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      Includes photographs of the installation process and setup as well as preliminary drawings envisioning how the project will look.
    - Legal Material, circa 1974 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Reports on Environmental Impact and Construction, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8-9)
    - Financial Material (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Maps, circa 1974 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material, 1974-1980 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Undated Printed Material, circa 1976 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - "25 Years After Running Fence" Exhibition, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Christo's Valley Curtain, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Christo's Wrapped Reichstag, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Christo's Wrapped Walkways, circa 1977 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Christo's Wrapped Pont Neuf, 1976-1985 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Christo's Surrounded Islands, circa 1983 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Christo's Wrapped New York Times, June 13, 1985, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Congressional Hearings on "Recent Trends in Art Behind the Iron Curtain", 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - The Contemporary Mural Movement: A Symposium in Honor of Romare Bearden, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Contextual Symposium: A Challenge to Institutions, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Cuba Art Lectures, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Disney Project (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 25-27)
    - Notes, circa 1983 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Maps, circa 1983 (Box 13, Folder 29)
      Oversized material housed in OV 33.
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Film Series on Expressionism, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - The Exiles Documentary Correspondence, 1987-1996 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - The Exiles, 1989; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Funk Art Symposium (Box 13)
    - Panel Discussion Part 1, 1967; 1 sound tape reels (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Panel Discussion Part 2, 1967; 1 sound tape reels (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Panel Discussion, 1967; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Photographs, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Printed Material, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - International Association for Semiotic Studies Panel, 1978-1979 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Museum of Modern Art Oral History Project Peter Selz Interview, 1993-1994 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - National Peace Project Design Competition, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Opposition to George Segal's Holocaust Memorial Sculpture, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Preservation of Gottard Piazzoni Murals, 1996-2000 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
  - Pop Art Panel Discussion, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Rosenberg Era Art Project, 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - University of Minnesota Grant Application for "The Artist as Social Critic in Germany" Program, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Oversized Disney Project Maps from Box 13, Folder 29, circa 1983 (Box OV 33)
- Membership and Association Records, 1958-2013; Series 5; 0.8 Linear feet Box 14-15
  Membership and association records document Selz’s involvement with or membership in various art councils, trustee boards, such as the College Art Association, Art in Chicago Advisory Committee, Bay Area Rapid Transit (B.A.R.T.) Art Council, and the San Francisco Crafts and Folk Art Museum Advisory Board, among others. Materials include meeting minutes, bulletins, correspondence, and memoranda.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Archives of American Art West Coast Advisory Committee, 1991-2002 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Art in Chicago Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Art in Chicago Advisory Committee Correspondence and Memorandums, 1993-1997 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Artists for Amnesty Committee, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) Art Council, 1973-1980 (Box 14, Folder 14-17)
  - College Art Association of American Board, 1958-1962 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Council for Creative Projects, 1992-1999 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Fulbright Program Committee, 1961-1966 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Institute for Living Arts Board, 1989-1993 (Box 14, Folder 21-22)
  - Meridian Gallery Society for Art Publications of the Americas Board, 2005-2013 (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
  - Mexican Museum Curator Search Committee, 1989-1999 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - San Francisco Arts Commission, 1983-1986 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - San Francisco Crafts & Folk Art Museum Advisory Board, 1982-1991 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - UNICEF Art for Children's Survival Committee, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - University of California Berkeley Art Museum Council, 1966-1974 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Artists' Research Files, 1955-2014; Series 6; 7.9 Linear feet Box 15-22, OV 34-35
  Found here are research files compiled and organized by Peter Selz about artists. Files may include original and photocopied correspondence, photographs, negatives, slides, articles, clippings, artist statements, resumes, and writings. Artists include Bedri Baykam, Max Beckmann, Fletcher Benton, Ciel Bergman, Barbara Chase-Riboud, Bruce Conner, Jean Dubuffet, Lyonel Feininger, Leon Golub, Dimitri Hadzi, Tobi Kahn, Christopher Lane, Rico Lebrun, Harold Paris, Irving Petlin, and many others. There are also 11 CDs and 1 sound cassette.
  - Abeles, Kim, 2003-2005 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Abrams, Maria Frank, 2003-2009 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Albright, Ivan, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Altoon, John, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Anthony, Gene, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Antin, Eleanor, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Arneson, Robert, 1981-2006 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Ariel, 1997-2006 (Box 15, Folder 15-16)
  - Arnold, Chester, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Avalos, David, circa 2003 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Aylon, Helene, 1988-2006 (Box 15, Folder 19-21)
  - Baca, Judith, 2000-2004 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Barrish, Jerry, 2002-2007 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Baskin, Leonard, 1961-1993 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Battenberg, John, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Baykam, Bedri (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1986-2009 (Box 15, Folder 26-27)
    - "Bedri Baykam: Xenophobia and Expressionist Dramas" Draft, circa 1986 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Printed Material, 1985-circa 1988 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Photographs and Slides, 1985-1986 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Beasley, Bruce, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Beckmann, Max (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1964-2008 (Box 15, Folder 32-33)
    - Writings, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Printed Material, 1964-1967 (Box 15, Folder 35)
      Oversized material housed in OV 34.
  - Beldner, Ray, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Benton, Fletcher, 1966-2013 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Benton, Fletcher, "Napa Valley Sculpture Garden", circa 2000; Includes 1 sound disc (CD). (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bergman, Ciel, 1992-2009; Includes 2 sound discs (CD). (Box 16, Folder 4-7)
  - Birk, Sandow, 2000-2005 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Boise, Ron, 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Bovenzi, Eva, 2007-2014 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Bowers, Cheryl, 1977-1987 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Burkhardt, Hans, 2002-2008 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Bury, Pol, 1969-2006 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Caja, Jerome, 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Carosone, Paolo, 1966-1976 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Carrillo, Eduardo, 1995-2005 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Chagall, Marc, 1961-1981 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Chagoya, Enrique, 1994-2001 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Chamberlain, Ann, 2001-2002 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Chase-Riboud, Barbara (Box 16)
    - Biographical Material, 1966-1994 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Harry Abrams, Inc. Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - General Correspondence, 1998-2008 (Box 16, Folder 22-23)
    - Photocopy of Amnesia: Collected Poems, circa 1998 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Negatives, circa 1998 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Harry Abrams Publishing Agreement, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Notes, circa 1998 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Chase-Riboud, Barbara (Box 17)
    - Typescript Drafts, circa 1998 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Typescript Draft and Book Cover, circa 1998 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material, 1998-2001 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Chicago, Judy, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Chipp, Herschel B., 1992 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Colescott, Robert, 2002-2009 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Conal, Robbie, 2000-2003 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Conner, Bruce, 1962-2005 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
  - Cutler-Shaw, Joyce, 1984-2004 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - DeMarinis, Paul, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Denes, Agnes, 2004-2006 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - De Staebler, Stephen, 1987-2009 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Dickinson, Eleanor, 1991-1994 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - di Rosa Collection, 1991-1998 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - di Suvero, Mark, 1995-2002 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Dubuffet, Jean (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1967 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - "The Essential Duality of Jean Dubuffet" Lecture Draft, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Research File for Lecture, circa 1962 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Duffy, Ricardo, 1997-2002 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Erskine, Peter, 1992-2004 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Everts, Connor, 2001-2003 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Faragher, Kristina, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Fein, Clinton, 2004-2007; Includes 1 sound disc (CD). (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Feininger, Lyonel, 1987-2006 (Box 17, Folder 25-27)
  - Fonseca, Harry, 2003-2005 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Forkscrew Graphics, circa 2004 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Foulkes, Llyn, 1987-2005 (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
  - Freimark, Robert, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Garcia, Rupert, 1980-1986 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Garrett, J. C., circa 2004 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Gentry, Herbert, 1983-1991 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Gerbault, Alain, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Giacometti, Alberto, 1965-1970 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Glaubman, Evelyn, 2002-2004 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Golub, Leon (Box 18)
    - Leon Golub Correspondence, 1955-1982 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      Correspondence between Peter Selz and Leon Golub.
    - Photocopies of Leon Golub Correspondence, 1955-1982 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1955-1960 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      Correspondence between Selz and others about exhibitions and books on Leon Golub.
    - Printed Material, 1961-1985 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Graham, Patrick, 2010-2012 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Graves, Morris, 2003-2004 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Greenberg, Jules, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Grillo, John, 1997-2012 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Gronk, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Grosz, George, 2003-2006 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Gu, Wenda, circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Hadzi, Dmitri (Box 18)
    - Photocopies of Letters to Dmitri Hadzi from Various Correspondents, circa 1960-circa 1988 (Box 18, Folder 23)